GIRISHA.C

UI / UX / Front-end Developer

Cell: +91 9620334248

#41, Ground floor, 2nd Cross, New Bank Colony, Near Silicon School, JP Nagar 7th Phase, Konanakunte, Bengaluru - 560062

Website: https://cgirish.github.io Email: grsh84@gmail.com

I'm a UI/UX designer with strong Front-end Development skills, with **11+ years of Industrial Experience**. I focus on doing what I love, the web is my favorite platform for realizing new ideas. I am a perfectionist when it comes to pixel perfect designs and well-documented code.

On any given day, I design user-interfaces, building mobile-friendly websites, landing pages, and web apps, and managing content in and out of a CMS with the help of HTML, CSS, and Javascript. This enables me to work through designs from early problem solving to high fidelity prototypes.

Deep understanding of this process enables me to better communicate the project requirements and constraints with the team or take complex challenges on independently.

During my free time, I love to solve issue in Stack Overflow, work on 3D graphics using Blender and SVG!

Skills and Day-to-Day Comfort:

User Experience Design, User Interface Design, Front-End Development, Rapid Prototyping, WordPress Themes, Joomla Themes, Prototyping, and Wireframing.

- CSS3 / SCSS / PostCSS
- HTML5 / HAML / Zeplin
- JavaScript / jQuery / ReactJS / Vue.js
- Mobile First Thinking, Responsive Layout and Design
- Cross-Browser Compatibility

- Workflow Tools Balsamiq / Invision
- CSS Frameworks Foundation / Bootstrap
- Version Control GIT (Github / Gitlab)
- **Graphic Design -** Photoshop / Sketch / Illustrator
- Agile Methodology

EXPERIENCE

Codemancers, **Bangalore** — *Creative Head*

OCT 2012 - AUG 2018 (5 years, 11 months)

I've worked as a Front-end Developer, UI/UX Designer and as a Lead in the role of Creative Head.

I was a part of ClearTax GST and EWAY-Bill project's Front-end team, where I led the UI design and Front-end Development along with few other designers and developers between June 2017 till August 2018.

My Responsibilities:

- Designing & Creating UI mock-ups and workflows using Sketch, Balsamiq, Invision.
- Developing the front-end web application for the project using ReactJS.

In addition, I worked alongside CA's, Marketing Researcher, Content Strategist and 4 Product Managers.

Projects at Codemancers Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

React Apps

Cleartax GST App (https://cleartax.in/gst, https://gst.cleartax.in/login)

Cloud based GST Software for Enterprises. Simplify GST Returns, generate GST compliant invoices & much more

<u>Cleartax EWAY Bill App</u> (https://ewb.cleartax.in/login)

Create Eway Bills accurately with our simple & intelligent EWay Bill Software

Jekyll App

: ClearTax (https://cleartax.in/)

Chrome Extensions : Interceptor (https://github.com/code-mancers/interceptor)

TIL - Learn and grow every day! (https://github.com/code-mancers/littil.ext, http://www.littil.io/)

Littil's browser extensions for firefox and chrome browsers

<u>Dockup-ui</u> (https://github.com/code-mancers/dockup-ui)

UI for dockup and chatops_deployer(until dockup makes it obsolete).

ROR Apps

BrightBox (https://www.brightbox.com/, https://manage.brightbox.com/login)

<u>Midtrans</u> earlier it was called <u>Veritrans</u> (https://account.midtrans.com/login) <u>Veritrans App</u> (https://citrusapp.herokuapp.com/), <u>IRIS App - styleguide</u> (<a href="https://iris-

uikit.herokuapp.com/)

WeLab website (https://www.welab.co/en), WeLend App (https://www.welend.hk/en/)

Using this app, disbursement of loan amount into customers bank account will be made automatically after the loan agreement has been signed online. Get your rate first, Submit your documents later to WeLend.hk or through WhatsApp

Ivrnet Central – Recreation, Membership & Facilities Management (https://ivrnet.com/, https://central.ivrnet.com/, https://central.ivrnet.com/) <a href="

GFI portal (https://gfi.com/, https://partners.gfi.com/)

It enables IT administrators to easily and efficiently discover, manage and secure their business networks, systems, applications and communications wherever they exist.

<u>Invoker</u> (http://invoker.codemancers.com/, https://github.com/code-mancers/invoker) Invoker is a gem for managing processes in development environment.

Rbkit (http://rbkit.codemancers.com, https://github.com/code-mancers/rbkit)

Rbkit is a Ruby gem that plugs into your ruby process, taps profiling data in realtime and sends it across the wire to the rbkit-client as packed messages.

Rbkit Client - Rbkit Desktop application (https://github.com/code-mancers/rbkit-client)
Rbkit is a profiler built with ease of use in mind. Currently it supports memory profiling

Rapidfire (https://github.com/code-mancers/rapidfire) Making dynamic surveys should be easy!

Diffity (https://github.com/code-mancers/diffity.rb)

Ruby gem to integrate with integration-diff

Elixir App : Dockup (https://github.com/code-mancers/dockup/tree/k8s-ui)

Automated disposable staging environments for your services

Castle Rock Research, Bangalore — Web Designer

APR 2010 - OCT 2012 (2 years, 7 months)

Was assigned to large-scale projects where design was the primary emphasis. Worked on projects ranging from small, 2-man WordPress Site to 15-man Web App using Ruby on Rails. Used Agile Methodology, Git for Version Control and Sass on all projects. Presented creative solutions to large-scale design challenges from clients. Helped bridge departmental gaps and acquired new skill sets by collaborating closely with development during projects. Primary code utilization included HTML5, CSS3, Sass, JavaScript, and Git.

Projects at CastleRock Research India Pvt. ltd.

ROR Apps : SOLARO (http://www.solaro.com/)

SOLARO Application (https://app.solaro.com/)
DocXchange(https://app.solaro.com/)

SOLARO India(http://www.solaro.in/).

Mobile Apps : iPhone:

SOLARO Responder (http://itunes.apple.com/in/app/solaro-responder/id409215922?mt=8, SOLARO Mobile http://itunes.apple.com/in/app/solaro-mobile/id368405914?mt=8).

<u>iPad:</u>

SOLARO Respond (http://itunes.apple.com/in/app/solaro-respond/id409213137?mt=8).

Android:

SOLARO (http://www.appbrain.com/app/solaro%E2%84%A2-parent/com.solaro.parent).

PHP Apps : Castle Rock Corporate (http://www.castlerockresearch.com),

Castle Rock India (http://www.castlerockresearch.in), besuperman.org (http://www.besuperman.org).

Mac App : DocXchange App for Mac OS

Windows App: DocXchange App for Windows OS (Using Microsoft Expression Blend and .Net)

Agiline Inc, Bangalore — Web and Graphic Designer

JAN 2007 - APR 2010 (3 years, 4 months)

Handled all web design for 50+ clients. Created all web-based email designs and marketing designs such as postcards, web banners, flyers, and anything else at the client's request.

Projects at Agiline India Pvt. Ltd

HTML Projects Out sourced projects from CrystalDI.com (http://www.athleticsingles.com/,

http://www.avkinkade.com/, http://www.awrapitis.com/, http://www.beulahflyrods.com/,

http://www.bhagatsinghthind.com/testimonies.html,

http://www.crenshawdocumentprep.com/, http://www.crystaldi.com/,

http://www.crystaldi.com/daveed/, http://www.delriolanes.com/, http://www.forestlanes.com/,

http://www.jimmybondmusic.com/, http://www.keystonelanes.com/, ,

http://www.otherbar.org/donate.html, http://www.vectorstudios.com/, http://www.visions-

opera.com/).

DotNetNuke

Rialto Recreations (http://rialtorec.net),

Projects Enigma Saves (http://www.enigmasaves.com/),

Farias Jett (http://www.fariasjett.com/),

Turk International (http://www.turk-international.com/),

InfiniTek (http://www.infinitek.biz/), Averiware (http://www.averiware.com), Agiline (http://www.agiline.com/),

Jurupa (http://jcsd.us/),

Surf it Local (http://www.surfitlocal.com/).

ASP.NET Projects

SIGMAnet (http://www.sigmanet.com/), SIGMAnet Online (https://online.sigmanet.com/).

SBDC and all its sub sites:

Lead Center (http://www.smallbizla.org/),

College of the Canyons (http://www.sbdc4biz.org/), EI Camino College (http://www.southbaysbdc.org/),

Long Beach City College (http://www.longbeachsbdc.org/),

Pacific Coast Regional (http://207.233.66.61/pacificcoastregional/Default.aspx),

Mt. San Antonio College (http://www.SanGabrielValleySBDC.org/),

Santa Monica College (http://www.smcsbdc.com/),

Ventura College (http:/www.vcsbdc.com/).

Surf it Local (http://www.surfitlocal.com/),

Accuchex (https://one.time2pay.accuchex.com/),

Pell Air Heating and Air Conditioning Inc(http://www.pellair.com/),

iCastDeals (http://www.icastdeals.com/), Tix4Tonight (http://www.tix4tonight.com/),

Anne-Sophie films (http://www.annesophiefilms.com/).

Flash Project : Knowing You Knowing Me (http://www.knowingyou-knowingme.com/).

Education

2005 - 2006 : ADIT (Advanced Diploma in Information Technology) with an Aggregate of 88.4% in Centre for

Information Science and Technology (CIST), Manasagangothri, Mysore. [Mysore University]

2002 - 2005 : BSc [PEM (Physics, Electronics and Math's) as optional] with an Aggregate of 60.5% in Yuvaraja's

college, Mysore. [Mysore University]

Personal Details

DOB : 1st March 1984

Can speak : Kannada, English, Hindi, and Telugu

Marital Status: Married

I hereby declare that the above-mentioned details are true to the best of my knowledge.

Girisha. C